Rachel Magley

Bay Area, CA e: rachelmagley@gmail.com c: +1.415.640.9665

<u>Portfolio GitHub LinkedIn</u>

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Full stack developer applying a curious, strategic, and analytical mindset. Prioritizes ongoing professional and personal growth and development, with efficiency as a key driver. Ability to easily transition between big picture and small details in order to communicate effectively and deliver comprehensive results. 13+ years of previous corporate retail merchant experience with extensive cross-functional partnership and global strategic development.

SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks:

HTML | CSS3 | Sass | JavaScript | React | Node | Express | AJAX | Python | Django

Databases, Management & Deployment:

SQL | PostgreSQL | MongoDB | API's | Git/Github | Terminal

Highlights:

Data Analysis | Problem Solving | Cross-functional Collaboration | Talent Management & Development | Process Efficiency C-Suite Presenting Skills | Global Strategic Development

PROJECTS

Divers Discovery | Github Link Front End | Github Link Back End | Deployed Pages Link

Full stack tool coded in React using JavaScript and CSS, supported by a backend coded in PostgreSQL, Python and Django.

Color Theory | Github Link | Deployed Pages Link

Utilizes front end software languages CSS & JavaScript created in React. Interactive design producing curated color schemes.

The Game of Memory | Github Link | Deployed Pages Link

Utilizes front end software languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript and responsive designing to implement game logic.

Flex Five | Github Link | Deployed Pages Link

Group collaboration utilizing the full stack including MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, React and Node.js.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

STUDENT

General Assembly

November 2021 - February 2022 New York, NY

• Completed 12 week, 500 hour remote Software Engineer Immersive Program utilizing critical programming skills to design, build and deploy a multitude of projects in both solo and collaborative environments.

GLOBAL MERCHANDISE MANAGER, BEAUTY, LIQUOR, TOBACCO, SUNDRIES Starboard Cruise Services, LVMH Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton

March 2018 - June 2021 Miami, FL

Global Travel Retail Strategy:

- Lead a team of 6 across consumables category within #1 travel retail cruise industry company. Ownership of 25% to total company business, with comparable growth year over year. Created and implemented global merchandise strategies to ensure beat to budget and previous year figures.
- Accountable for Beauty Department P&L, responsible for negotiating and executing profit initiatives with brands. Talent Management & Development:
- Leadership of 6 employees with 2 employee promotions under management within 18 months.

Chicago, IL

Ulta Beauty

Managed merchandise strategy and relationship for 5 key brands within Prestige Cosmetics department, equal to over \$500M in
annual sales, with positive annual growth and performance to budget in every brand. Managed high profile brand relationships for
the company. Recognized as a subject matter expert of the industry.

• Launched 2 exclusive to Ulta Beauty brands in 12 months. Assessed sales potential, created 360 launch plans with cross-functional teams, drove visual merchandise strategy, monitored performance and provided feedback to course correct.

BUYER Amazon Corporate LLC July 2014 - February 2015 Seattle, WA

Buying & Merchandise Strategy:

- Managed beginning to end on-boarding process for 70+ luxury beauty brands including introduction to Amazon.com vendor
 platform, assortment creation, item set up, pricing, opening order projections, supply chain flow, and marketing/merchandising
 strategy and execution.
- Intensive reporting and analysis of competitive pricing metrics, various profit factors and sales by brand on a weekly basis to identify strengths, opportunities and risks. Implemented strategies accordingly.

Process Improvement:

Scaled existing process for launching 1-3 brands per month to accommodate 15+ brands per month. Identified ways to automate
processes to meet high-touch needs of brands.

ASSISTANT BUYER April 2011 - July 2014

Sephora, LVMH Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton S.A.

San Francisco, CA

- Partnered closely with product development teams, international and domestic vendors to create strategy to achieve long-term brand vision of #1 sales brand. Simultaneously acted as the merchant and the brand.
- Analyzed and reported sales of key categories to achieve sales and GM targets.
- 2 years of Third-Party Brand Management with Sephora inside JCPenney department. Devised multi-million-dollar annual sales plan strategy with key brand representatives and both Sephora and JCPenney teams.

DISTRIBUTION ANALYST

February 2010 - April 2011

Sephora, LVMH Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton S.A.

San Francisco, CA

- Promoted to Assistant Buyer after one year.
- Created, managed, and maintained balanced SKU inventory levels at store and warehouse locations.
- Developed stocking strategies for fast-turning merchandise.

MERCHANDISE PLANNING ASSISTANT

November 2008 - February 2010

Sephora, LVMH Moët Hennessy Louis Vuitton S.A.

San Francisco, CA

- Supported supply chain and planning teams through reporting, SKU creation and maintenance, PO creation and tracking.
- Streamlined role from two positions into one position. On-boarded my replacement.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive, Full Stack Web Development

BA—Michigan State University, East Lansing, Michigan. College of Communication Arts & Sciences, Advertising